<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<TitlePage>
  <Title>
    Alnuth
  </Title>
  <Subtitle>
    ALgebraic NUmber THeory<Alt Only="LaTeX"><Br/></Alt>
    and an interface to<Alt Only="LaTeX"><Br/></Alt>
    PARI/GP and OSCAR
  </Subtitle>
  <Version>
    &VERSION;
  </Version>
  <TitleComment>
    <E>Note:</E> PARI/GP is <E>not</E> part of this package. It can be
    obtained from <URL>https://pari.math.u-bordeaux.fr/</URL>. If you use GAP
    via OSCAR, then OSCAR will automatically be used instead of PARI/GP.
  </TitleComment>
  <Author>
    GAP code by Björn Assmann, Andreas Distler and Bettina Eick
  </Author>
  <Author>
    PARI/GP code by Bill Allombert
  </Author>
  <Author>
    OSCAR code by Claus Fieker and Max Horn
  </Author>

  <Date>
    &RELEASEDATE;
  </Date>

  <Copyright>
    This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
    it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
    the Free Software Foundation, either version 2 of the license, or
    (at your option) any later version.
    <P/>

    This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
    but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
    MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
    GNU General Public License for more details.
    <P/>

    You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
    along with this program. If not, see <URL>https://www.gnu.org/licenses/</URL>
    <P/>
  </Copyright>

  <Acknowledgements>
    To begin with we are very grateful for all the feedback by users of
    former versions of &Alnuth;.
    <P/>

    We thank Bill Allombert who wrote the GP code for the interface to
    PARI/GP and who was extremely helpful in the transition from KANT
    to PARI/GP.
    <P/>

    For feedback on the development version, including a code patch, we
    are much obliged to Max Horn.
    <P/>

    The second author acknowledges the financial support at CAUL within
    the projects PTDC/MAT/101993/2008 and ISFL-1-143, financed by FEDER
    and FCT, in the development of Version 3 of &Alnuth;.
    <P/>

    Support for using OSCAR instead of PARI/GP was added by Claus Fieker
    and Max Horn.
    <P/>
  </Acknowledgements>

</TitlePage>
